Wes Henderson

I am a community oriented Linux nerd with more than a decade of IT experience and a penchant for automation and mentoring. I believe that continuous improvement, both in process and tech, is paramount for any organization. The key to maintaining continuous improvement is to build and maintain a strong team through constant, organic training. This promotes knowledge sharing and helps the team adapt to changing workplace priorities.

Skills

- Keenly aware of operations and ever mindful of opportunities for process improvement.
- Passionate about mentoring and collaboration.
- Skilled technical writer with a love for documentation.
- Ability to quickly acclimate to new software.
- Advanced scripting skills with Bash and Powershell.
- Intermediate programming skills, primarily with Python.
- Proficient with config management and infrastructure as code: Ansible, Chef, Puppet, Salt, Terraform, and CloudFormation
- Automation experience with Python, boto3 (AWS SDK), and Fabric.
- Intimate understanding of public cloud infrastructure.
- Familiar with modern software design principles such as SoA and Microservices.
- Expert Google'ite.

Experience

Lead Systems Engineer | Salesforce | November 2019-Present

- Led a small team on our 'Bring Your Own Key' (BYOK) initiative; this product allowed customers to fully own the keys their databases were encrypted with and represented \$6 million in recurring revenue for Pardot.
- Helped to identify and deploy cost saving measures in our public cloud infrastructure, representing a savings of \$3 million dollars annually.
- Led multiple teams across multiple business units in order to meet deployment deadlines.
- Built a bespoke tooling pipeline for the SRE team, allowing tools to be created and shared widely while circumventing common pitfalls around such tooling, e.g. tribal knowledge resulting in decreased visibility and adoption.
- Built a CLI tool to rapidly manage asynchronous jobs, greatly decreasing response time while increasing visibility.

Deployment Engineer | TrueAbility | December 2017-November 2019

- Mentored junior team members and built pathways from support to engineering.
- Helped many top companies build, deploy, and grade their performance based assessments.
- Acted as a consultant on exam creation and deployment.
- Created bespoke environments/grading via Bash and Powershell, primarily.
- Contributed to the underlying codebase where applicable.
- Maintained the AWS and GCP infrastructure for internal tooling and exams respectively.

DevOps Engineer | Rackspace Hosting | March 2017-December 2017

- Architect and deploy scalable cloud solutions for customers in an AWS ecosystem via CloudFormation.
- Design for customers' regulatory requirements (e.g. PCI, HIPPA, etc).
- Educate customers on distributed computing principles and CI/CD solutions.
- Collaborate with team members via GitHub.
- Wrote a Python framework to automate the build process.

- Created custom tooling in Bash and Python.
- Active contributor to both the internal Rackspace wiki and public blog.

Education

Northwest Vista College | January 2010-May 2012

- Associate of Applied Science in Computer Forensics with a 4.0 GPA
- Marketable Skills Achievement Award: Linux RHCT
- Marketable Skills Achievement Award: Information Security & Assurance

Certifications

Cert	License
AWS Certified Solutions Architect	AWS-ASA-29789
Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHCE), 2016	130-119-274
Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA), 2013	130-119-274
Linux Professional Institute Certification 1 (LPIC-1), 2012	LPI000250530
Novell Certified Linux Administrator (CLA), 2012	10176504
Novell Data Center Technical Specialist, 2012	10176504
CompTIA Linux+, 2012	COMP001007825623
CompTIA Security+, 2010	COMP001007825623
CompTIA Network+, 2010	COMP001007825623
CompTIA A+, 2008	COMP001007825623